credentials-inc.com 2009-06-18

# Security and Privacy Policies | Credentials Solutions

**_Our Commitment To Privacy_**  
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the way your information is collected and used. Orders processed on our web sites are accepted solely on behalf of institutions that have contracted with us for processing services (generally colleges, universities, and municipalities). To make this notice easy to find, we make it available through our homepage and on all of our order entry pages. 

**_Who We Are and How We Conduct Our Business_**  
Our companies, Credentials Inc. and Credentials Order Processing Services Inc., have collectively been in business since 1997. We provide Internet-based order processing and services as a contracted agent for various colleges, universities, municipalities, and other related industry institutions. It is on behalf of these institutions that we are accepting your order and providing services to you. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, the term "outside parties" is therefore any person, company, or entity that is NOT one of our contracted institutions. 

**_The Information We Collect_**  
When placing an order on our site, you may be asked to enter personal information such as your name, e-mail address, mailing/billing address, phone number, cell phone number (optional), fax telephone number (optional), credit card information, student identification number and/or social security number (depending on individual institutional requirements). 

**_How We Use Your Information_**  
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any outside parties for any reason whatsoever other than to the institution on whose behalf we are processing your order and only for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested. 

Credit card information is used exclusively to process the charges related to your transaction. We transmit credit/debit card transaction information to our credit card servicing company using SSL-based encrypted communications. Following accepted industry guidelines, we may retain your credit card number for up to 60 days following the completion of your transaction. This retention period facilitates our handling of refunds and resolution of any disputed charges. 

Credit card information is never provided to the institutions on whose behalf we process your order or to any other outside parties. 

Any e-mail address, cell phone number (optional for text messaging), or fax telephone number you provide for order processing will only be used to send you information and status updates pertaining to your order. We do not provide this information to any other person or outside party. 

**_How We Protect Your Information_**  
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have implemented a variety of security measures to safeguard your personal information when you place an order. We have in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Using our secure server, all web pages (not just those with social security numbers or credit/debit card numbers) utilized in our order processing systems are transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology. 

All of our employees are subjected to professionally-conducted background checks. Other than when accepting orders over the telephone, access by our employees to credit/debit card numbers is restricted. All access to full credit card numbers (including phone orders) is tracked and monitored. 

Credit/debit card numbers and social security numbers are stored using industry-standard strong-encryption technology. 

**_Use of Cookies_**  
We do not use cookies on any of our web pages. 

**_No Disclosure to Outside Parties_**  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties any information provided by you. This does not include the institutions on whose behalf we act as agent in accepting your order. We may release your information only if we believe such release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. 

**_California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance_**  
Because we value your privacy, we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We will therefore not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent. 

**_Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance_**  
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. 

**_Your Consent_**  
By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy. 

**_Changes to Our Privacy Policy_**  
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below. 

This policy was last modified on April, 2, 2009 

**_How To Contact Us_**  
Should you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below: 

Credentials Inc. / Credentials Order Processing Services Inc.  
436 W Frontage Road  
Northfield, IL 60093 

E-Mail: [ customerservice@credentialssolutions.com](mailto:customerservice@credentialssolutions.com)

Telephone: (847) 716-3000
